It's not human, and it's got an axe!
The Prey is a horror film directed by Edwin Brown.
Three couples go on a camping trip in the woods of southern California
during the summer, where a deformed man is stalking their camp.
Nancy, played by Debbie Thureson.
Joel, played by Steve Bond.
Bobbie, played by Lori Lethin.
Skip, played by Robert Wald.
Gail, played by Gayle Gannes.
Greg, played by Philip Wenckus.
The Prey  is a 1983 American slasher film directed by Edwin Brown, and starring
Debbie Thureson, Steve Bond, Lori Lethin, and Jackie Coogan.
It follows a group of campers in the Rocky Mountains who are
stalked and murdered by a disfigured assailant.
Inspired by such films as The Hills Have Eyes (1977), the screenplay was written by director Brown
and his wife, Summer, for Essex Productions, a studio specializing in adult films.
Brown was previously a producer on one of their features, the
softcore thriller Human Experiments (1979).
Filming took place in late 1979 in Idyllwild, California.
It was the final film credit of Coogan, who died in 1984.
The Prey was acquired for distribution by New World Pictures, and theatrically released in
the United States in November 1983, nearly four years after completion.
It was concurrently shown on premium television in Canada, and
later released on VHS by Thorn EMI in 1988.
In 2019, Arrow Films completed a restoration and released it on Blu-ray, marking
the film's first home media release in North America since 1988.
Contemporary critical opinion has varied, with its sparse
dialogue and pacing being points of criticism.
Other film scholars have praised its languorous pacing, which
accelerates considerably in the final act.
The film explores themes of camping, woods, slasher.
The tone is dark.